Rachid Belferar









Senior English Teacher



I am a dynamic, passionate, highly capable professional, and above all a quintessential qualified English teacher with a focus on students' learning and engagement. Experienced educator and facilitator with several years of service in teaching, particularly in the postsecondary academic settings. Exceedingly dedicated to teaching the principles of applied linguistics to college and university levels' learners, including all the aspects of the English language skills; listening, speaking, reading, and writing, both methodically and proactively. Exceptional proficiency of delivering teaching with technology and empowering students to use a huge variety of valuable recourses. Instil and share knowledge along with inspiring both children and adult learners, and implementing an effective behaviour management approach, alongside various motivational methods. Possessing excellent awareness and comprehension of diverse curriculum development and assessment methods based on a perpetual thorough research and practices.

Key Skills

- Create syllabuses from the ground up that detail the course, the assignments and their respective objectives for the semester.
- Excellent ability to facilitate and teach difficult concepts to students, including breaking down topics, scaffolding, reteaching for understanding.
- Meritorious oral and written communication skills when delivering lectures to students and communicating with staff or other members of the university.
- Constantly and perpetually evaluating work appropriately and make suggestions to help students grow academically.
- Dexterity to foster favourable and supportive relationships with students and other faculty members.
- Tremendously motivated to work independently, achieve my person best, and be a contributing member of the university community.
- Endowed with strength to persist despite obstacles, such lack of resources, a limited amount of class time, and other challenges in the classroom.
- Produce and publish on-line core teaching material as well as supplementary and essential apparatus to further support students' learning acquisition outside the classroom.

Technical Proficiencies

Platforms: Windows 7/8/10 Windows Server 2008 R2 and 2012 R2, Linux (Ubuntu, Xubuntu, Manjaro) & Cisco IOS Languages: C, VBScript, VB.Net, VBA, JavaScript, CSS, ASP.Net, SQL, HTML, Python.

Software & Tools: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, OneNote, Visio),

WordPress, and various Hypervisors (MS Hyper-V, VMware, VirtualBox, Qemu).

Teaching Tools: Moodle, Google Classroom, Minecraft Education Edition, Zoom, and several other tools.

Professional Experience

04/2011 – 10-2018 ALC / ELA / ESAA (French University) / Pasteur Institute (and various schools) Algiers - DZ 10/2018 - To present. EIS (Elegant International School) Cambodia, and in several schools (Malaysia, Vietnam) **Full Time Senior English Teacher**

- Conduct lectures each day for undergraduate and graduate-level courses on a variety of topics related to English literature, business, or language.
- Create course materials, assessments, projects, and a syllabus for each course in Business English and literature studies for all semester and for different class levels.
- Develop a scope and sequence of learning activities using course objectives, curriculum standards, and students' learning goals.
- Evaluate students' works, such as literary writing, research papers, and analysis tasks, by using teacherdeveloped rubrics and holistic practices.
- Effectively maintaining interests and providing interactive atmosphere, enabling students to significantly hone learning skills. Setting up and developing dynamic interactive websites' platforms to enrich students' learning experience.

- Instituting positive classroom management strategies and disciplinary programmes that effectively handle challenging behaviour issues.
- Collaborating with fellow teachers and next of kin the take the appropriate action plan in order to propel the student learning experience, providing extracurricular tutorial and emailing additional materials.

2002- 2011 Gap (Gap UK) PLC United Kingdom - London

System Administrator (2002 to 2007) System/Network Consultant (2009 to 2011)

Appointed as a full-time System/Network Consultant following initial System Administrator role. Provided Windows/Linux administration, network operation centre (NOC) administration, LAN/WAN/VPN administration, VMware administration, and Network Intrusion Detection System / Intrusion Prevention System (NIDS/NIPS) monitoring. Also managed FTP server, DNS/DHCP, wireless access points and load balancers. Design and implemented highly available (HA) and disaster recovery (DR) solutions for clients and employer.

Key Contributions:

- Directed the design, implementation, configuration and performance tuning of Cisco Routers and Switches (L2 & L3) environment for the company's district branches operations. Delivered a major improvement over old VLANs structure in replacing and updating Ethernet and Internet protocols.
- Evaluated and reconfigured company's Linux/Windows/SQL Servers setup, including reallocating NAS/SAN disks space to engineer a robust, scalable solution.
- Improved system security through setup and ongoing maintenance of Cisco Firewalls (ASA). Delivered a cohesive solution in creating and updating robust ACL for various network scenarios.
- Researched, recommended and implemented network enhancements that improved system reliability and performance.
- Planned, developed, coded, tested, administered several and diverse IT solutions, including numerous SQL Relational Database Management Systems (RDMS), Business Information Systems (BIS).
- Trained employees across multiple departments on using the IT infrastructure specifically the RDMS, BIS as well as network operations including log-in procedures, network management software, permissions, printing issues, security and use of software.

1998 -2002 Arcadia Group PLC (UK) United Kingdom - London

Computer System Engineer/Operation Manager

Provided on-site and remote support for one of the top UK retailer, including Tier-III support for LAN/WAN products and managed the operation department in supporting key business stores in creating innovative system solutions to increase sales and reduce shrinkage. Also, I collaborated with external auditors to conduct in-depth compliance audits and penetration testing, presenting results to senior management. Developed curricula and facilitate awareness training, as well as supervised daily activities of Computer Network Assistant and Internet Administration. *Key Contributions:*

- Managed server infrastructure and implemented several support procedures and company network design strategy for sales and operations teams.
- Developed highly effective Software Manager Application to enable analysing and tracking products locality and sales figures. Also developed a staff scheduling system which was rolled out across the board and as a result saved a colossal amount of money for the company.
- Compiled and wrote a security IT guidebook outlining the safe usage of company's IT infrastructure and peripherals by all teams across the board.
- Recognised for outstanding quality of customer service with numerous customer-support awards and personal commendation for clients.

Education, Training & Credentials

1987-1990	Lycée Des Sciences Techniques - Civil Engineering	Algiers - Beaulieu (Algeria)
1993-1995	Arbour Square College	London (United Kingdom)
2000-2002	Islington North London College	London (United Kingdom)
2002-2005	London Metropolitan University	London (United Kingdom)

Awards/Qualifications & Training

- Access Course Professional (high honours) Computer Science (Baccalaureate Certificate English)
- HNC (Hons), Computer Science (Software Engineering)
- HND (Hons), Computer Science (Software Engineering)
- CompTIA® (The Computing Technology Industry Association), A+
- BTEC Professional Development Award (English / Computer Science & Networking)
- TESOL (Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages)

References